ifpri.org 2019-08-10

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | IFPRI

(effective as of January 2018)

This policy aims to help you understand what information we collect about you and how we use it. This policy applies to IFPRI’s institutional websites (ifpri.org, ifpri.info, and IFPRI’s Facebook site, collectively referred to as “the Site”). IFPRI is committed to protecting your personal information.

**1\. What information IFPRI may collect about you**

_Personally identifiable information_

You are not asked to provide any personally identifiable information to access the Site. However, you will be asked to provide basic personal information such as your name, address, email address, and organizational affiliation to subscribe to email alerts or newsletters or to order publications, datasets, or other IFPRI products. And if you are applying for a job at IFPRI, you will be asked to provide the information routinely found in a curriculum vitae. IFPRI will store this information securely and will not share, rent, or sell it to any other organization.

If you choose to make a donation to IFPRI from our Facebook page, you will be asked to provide credit card information. IFPRI does not see or store this credit card information. Any credit card details are passed directly and securely to the payment processing partner and handled according to the Payment Card Industry Security Standards.

_Non-personally identifiable information_

In general, you can browse the Site without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. The only information we gather during general browsing is from standard server logs: these include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, operating system, and information such as the website that referred you to us, the files you download, the pages you visit, and the dates/times of those visits. These do not specifically identify you. The information is used only for website traffic analysis and is treated confidentially.

**2\. How IFPRI uses cookies**

A cookie is a small text file that a website saves on your computer or mobile device when you visit the site. There are multiple types of cookies, but cookies in general have two principle purposes:

  * to improve your browsing experience by remembering your actions and preferences
  * to facilitate analysis of website traffic

IFPRI uses cookies to facilitate analysis of website traffic. This helps us to improve the performance and usability of the Site and to better secure the Site. Specifically, IFPRI uses cookies to communicate with Google Analytics (for web traffic analysis) and Incapsula (for web performance and security). These third-party cookies are collected and managed anonymously and do not include any personally identifying information.

You can control or delete cookies as you wish; for details, see [https://www.aboutcookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/). You can delete all cookies that are already on your computer and you can set most browsers to prevent them from being placed. If you do this, however, you may have to manually adjust some preferences every time you visit a site and some services and functionalities may not work.

**3\. How IFPRI will use your information**

We will use your personally identifiable information for the purposes of:

  * giving you the products, information, or services you have requested
  * communicating with you about an event or conference
  * evaluating your job application
  * confirming receipt of donations
  * complying with financial regulations and the law

To do some of this, we may process your information using third party service providers or agents who may be located outside your home country. However, your information will only be used for the purposes you requested or agreed to or as required by law. Please see section 6 for more information on how we share your information with others.

We will use your non-personally identifiable information to facilitate analysis of website traffic to improve the performance and usability of the Site and to better secure the Site.

**4\. Your rights**

You can opt out of receiving emails from us at any time by unsubscribing using the link contained in the email or by sending a request to [IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org](mailto:IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org). You can also contact [IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org](mailto:IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org) to request to see your personal data, to request that we correct or delete your personal data, or to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data. You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority in your home country.

**5\. How IFPRI will protect your personal information**

We take appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial measures to ensure that we keep your information secure, accurate, and up to date. We will keep your data only as long as is reasonable and necessary or until you ask us to delete it.

**6\. Sharing your information with others**

IFPRI will keep your information confidential except where disclosure is required or permitted by law (for example to government bodies and law enforcement agencies) or as described in section 7 below.

We may transfer (or otherwise make available) your personal information to other members of the IFPRI organizational family.

Sometimes IFPRI uses third parties to process your information on our behalf. All of our service providers are required to maintain the confidentiality and security of your personal information and to use it only in compliance with applicable privacy laws. IFPRI requires these third parties to comply strictly with instructions that they not use your personal information for their own business purposes.

Due to the multinational character of IFPRI, some of the service providers, affiliated organizations, and other recipients may be located in countries (including the United States) that do not require a level of data protection equivalent to that in your home country. IFPRI will take appropriate steps to make sure that such recipients act in accordance with applicable law.

**7\. Offensive or inappropriate content on the Site**

If you post or send offensive, inappropriate, or objectionable content anywhere on or to the Site or otherwise engage in any disruptive behavior on any IFPRI service, IFPRI may use your personal information to stop such behavior.

Where IFPRI reasonably believes that you are or may be in breach of any applicable laws (e.g. because content you have posted may be defamatory or violate copyrights), IFPRI may use your personal information to inform relevant third parties such as law enforcement agencies about the content and your behavior.

**8\. Notification of Changes**

If IFPRI decides to change this Privacy Policy, IFPRI will post those changes to this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect and how we use it.

**9\. Contact Us**

If you have any questions or concerns about IFPRI’s Privacy Policy please do not hesitate to contact us.

Email address: [IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org](mailto:IFPRI-Info@cgiar.org)

Surface mail address:

IFPRI Privacy Policy Information

Communications and Public Affairs Division

1201 Eye St NW, 12th floor

Washington, DC 20005-3915 USA
